<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://maccraig.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://maccraig.net/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-23T19:33:44+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/</id><title type="html">Mackenzie Craig</title><subtitle>Personal website/blog</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Dance Pants</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-02/Dance-Pants" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dance Pants" /><published>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-02/Dance-Pants</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-02/Dance-Pants">&lt;p&gt;This is a relatively long term review of “Dance Pants” as a piece of backpacking gear. Dance pants are an extremely cheap and quite effective alternative to popular ultralight wind pants. I got these pants for under $20, which is a much better deal than the current high end ultralight offerings. They weigh in around 3oz on my scale, but this will vary with size. The pants seem to be popular with dancers for warming up before dancing, but they are simply thin ripstop nylon pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to keep this review simple, just like this product. I have been using these pants for several months and hundreds of miles and they do their job perfectly. They do not have pockets, or really any features at all. They are held up with an elastic waist, and held down at the ankles by more elastic. They are very flexible in terms of stretch and layering. I have worn them with just underwear underneath and have been comfortable, but have also worn the pants with underwear, shorts and a base layer underneath in cold conditions and had no issues. It does not feel like you are wearing an additional waistband when you layer these pants because they are so light and the waistband is so stretchy. I forget that I am wearing these pants a lot of the time while hiking or sleeping, but they do their job of adding some warmth and reducing wind well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can purchase the pants on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Body-Wrappers-Ripstop-Pants-Black/dp/B0002UR7SQ/&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, and I would really recommend that you pickup a pair if you are in the market for wind pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think they look too goofy, even though the name would suggest they might. I find they fit a lot like the classic champion closed bottom sweat pants. Here is a picture that I reluctantly took of myself wearing them for this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dance_pants_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dance Pants in action&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For sizing, I wear a medium. I am 5’11, and usually hover around 150lbs. I would recommend a medium if you are anywhere near my size, as they fit me pretty much perfectly. They stop before touching my shoes, which I like because it keeps them cleanish, but if you want them to sit lower, sizing up to a large could be an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: go for the black color if it is available for less see though potential. This could come in handy if you are doing laundry in town and you want to throw these on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Going_commando&quot;&gt;commando style&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is a relatively long term review of “Dance Pants” as a piece of backpacking gear. Dance pants are an extremely cheap and quite effective alternative to popular ultralight wind pants. I got these pants for under $20, which is a much better deal than the current high end ultralight offerings. They weigh in around 3oz on my scale, but this will vary with size. The pants seem to be popular with dancers for warming up before dancing, but they are simply thin ripstop nylon pants. I am going to keep this review simple, just like this product. I have been using these pants for several months and hundreds of miles and they do their job perfectly. They do not have pockets, or really any features at all. They are held up with an elastic waist, and held down at the ankles by more elastic. They are very flexible in terms of stretch and layering. I have worn them with just underwear underneath and have been comfortable, but have also worn the pants with underwear, shorts and a base layer underneath in cold conditions and had no issues. It does not feel like you are wearing an additional waistband when you layer these pants because they are so light and the waistband is so stretchy. I forget that I am wearing these pants a lot of the time while hiking or sleeping, but they do their job of adding some warmth and reducing wind well.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Backpacking Gear</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-01/Backpacking-Gear" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Backpacking Gear" /><published>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-01/Backpacking-Gear</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2019-01/Backpacking-Gear">&lt;p&gt;This post contains everything you might want to know about gear I use when backpacking, as well as some of my thoughts on gear choices. I have gotten some emails and messages about some items, so this is an effort to create something I can respond with. I am going to use this post as a place to link people to from other things such as future videos or posts as the one stop shop for my gear info. It will also contain some ramblings (more to come in the future) about gear and Ultralight ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many, I follow most of the principals of Ultralight Backpacking. You will see this in some of my gear choices, but admittedly not all. I try to keep my base weight as low as possible, but it often varies between trips. Generally my base weight is under 10lbs, often much lower if conditions permit. I live in Vancouver, Canada, so weather and conditions are constantly changing. When I am out around home, I am often switching things up or taking more or less gear to suit the conditions. If you live somewhere where you can be certain it isn’t going to rain for the next 5 days, then you can adapt your gear accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lighterpack.com/r/4qykgn&quot;&gt;My gear list&lt;/a&gt; is on LighterPack, which is a nice website for viewing gear lists, as well as maintaining your own. You might think it’s stupid to track your gear on a website, I know I did, but I think you’d be surprised with how useful it is. It is very helpful to be able to visualize all of your gear in the way that LighterPack allows you to, and it can help you pick out pieces of gear that are just too heavy, or things that you don’t need. Additionally, if you are prone to forgetting things, double check the gear in your pack against your list before heading out to make sure you have everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest anyone reading this puts their gear into LighterPack. If you have a cheap kitchen scale, it is perfect for weighing your gear. If you don’t, try to find weights from other peoples lists, or as a last resort from the manufacturer (it isn’t a huge deal if you are off by a bit). I think anyone would benefit from seeing where the weight on their back comes from in a more detailed way. A final note about LighterPack: I like to put all of my gear into one list, even the stuff that I rarely use, or only bring sometimes. Once you have done that, you can easily adjust the quantity of each item on the far right of each row, and just set it to zero if you don’t plan to bring it. I don’t care enough to maintain several lists, so this is the best way I have found to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in lightening your load, do not buy anything right away. At least for your first few trips, focus on getting rid of things you already have but don’t really need, and lighten your essential gear later. Do you need a stove or cook system? Try a trip where you cold soak your food and leave the stove at home. Remember, the lightest version of a given piece of gear isn’t the DCF or titanium version of it, it’s the one that you don’t bring at all. Once you are confident that you have reduced your load to only things that you require to be safe and relatively comfortable in the backcountry, then you can begin the gear research process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to tell you what to buy, because the stuff that I use works for me, and probably isn’t the best option for you. The best way to research gear is to speak with people who use that gear. If you are considering buying an item, take advantage of the gold mine of info online. &lt;a href=&quot;https://backpackinglight.com/&quot;&gt;Bacpacking Light&lt;/a&gt; is a great resource, but I prefer &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/ultralight&quot;&gt;/r/Ultralight&lt;/a&gt; (which is free). Both of those sites (as well as Google searches likely returning those sites) are your best friend. Check for gear reviews, trip reports using said item, or other threads posted by people in the same boat as you who are asking questions about the item. Almost all popular items are well documented with reviews and endless questions and answers from potential buyers, and you will likely find what you are looking for fairly easily. If you are having trouble finding an answer for a question with the techniques I just explained, you have a few options. First off, you could contact the company selling the item directly. Most cottage companies in the backpacking world are extremely friendly to potential buyers (for obvious reasons) and are often willing to provide detailed answers/measurements to any questions or requests you may have about their products. Another option is to reach out to someone who has the item. Most people will gladly answer your questions if you track down their email address or DM them on their socials (be cool). Lastly, if you really can’t decide or find the information you need, post on &lt;a href=&quot;https://reddit.com/r/ultralight&quot;&gt;/r/Ultralight&lt;/a&gt; and someone can hopefully help you out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are starting completely fresh, I would suggest you find some trip reports on Reddit from people who are hiking in areas that you plan on hiking (or places with similar conditions). Take note of the items that they bring and the items they don’t. I wouldn’t suggest you go out and buy all of the gear they have, but you could use their gear lists to get a general idea of what you will need. For example, if you are going to be hiking in the Appalachians and see that most Appalachian range hikers prepare for slightly wetter conditions than hikers who frequent the Arizona trail, you should aim to reflect this in your kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When buying gear, you will make mistakes, but being careful you can minimize those mistakes. Just make sure to put in the research and don’t make any impulse buys that you will regret later. Ultralight gear isn’t cheap, and also comes with some killer lead times in many cases, so it is best to put in the time and reap the rewards when you are happy with your gear. 8 weeks of lead time is a lot of time for buyers remorse if you aren’t sure what you want to purchase!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="test" /><summary type="html">This post contains everything you might want to know about gear I use when backpacking, as well as some of my thoughts on gear choices. I have gotten some emails and messages about some items, so this is an effort to create something I can respond with. I am going to use this post as a place to link people to from other things such as future videos or posts as the one stop shop for my gear info. It will also contain some ramblings (more to come in the future) about gear and Ultralight ideas. Like many, I follow most of the principals of Ultralight Backpacking. You will see this in some of my gear choices, but admittedly not all. I try to keep my base weight as low as possible, but it often varies between trips. Generally my base weight is under 10lbs, often much lower if conditions permit. I live in Vancouver, Canada, so weather and conditions are constantly changing. When I am out around home, I am often switching things up or taking more or less gear to suit the conditions. If you live somewhere where you can be certain it isn’t going to rain for the next 5 days, then you can adapt your gear accordingly!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dennett Lake</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-11/Dennett-Lake" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dennett Lake" /><published>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-11/Dennett-Lake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-11/Dennett-Lake">&lt;p&gt;This week my friend Riley and I hiked up to Dennett Lake, on Burke Mountain. The 21km hike took a total of about five and a half hours, but could be knocked down to four and a half if you were really on a mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed the same route to Munro Lake as detailed in &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2018-08/Rospe-Trail&quot;&gt;my last post&lt;/a&gt;, so I won’t make a new map for this post. If you want the exact route, you can check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/1954090304&quot;&gt;gps track&lt;/a&gt;. Once you are at Munro lake, you should see a bare cliff on the other side of the lake. Head north (towards the cliff) from the area that the trail enters the lake, across the dried up section, and follow the edge of the lake counter clockwise until you see the trail on your left. There are some blue blazes on the first kilometer or so of this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the route has some steep portions but requires no technical climbing (although there were some cool climbing spots on the north side of Dennett Lake). At this time of year, a fair bit of the ground was frozen at the higher elevations, as well as some smaller water sources. The big ones were just starting to freeze around the edges. If you plan to visit later than early November, bring a little bit of extra water, or have a way to melt some.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dennett_lake_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dennett Lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The picture above is an awesome camping spot we found at Dennett lake, big enough for two or three small shelters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail conditions get pretty dismal after Munro Lake. Most of the trail has become a stream, or a mud bog, and you may prefer to bushwhack at parts. If you are hiking when it’s wet, bring breathable shoes, because you are going to get wet no matter what you wear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more photos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dennett_lake_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dennett Lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dennett_lake_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dennett Lake&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This week my friend Riley and I hiked up to Dennett Lake, on Burke Mountain. The 21km hike took a total of about five and a half hours, but could be knocked down to four and a half if you were really on a mission. We followed the same route to Munro Lake as detailed in my last post, so I won’t make a new map for this post. If you want the exact route, you can check out my gps track. Once you are at Munro lake, you should see a bare cliff on the other side of the lake. Head north (towards the cliff) from the area that the trail enters the lake, across the dried up section, and follow the edge of the lake counter clockwise until you see the trail on your left. There are some blue blazes on the first kilometer or so of this area.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rospe Trail</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Rospe-Trail" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rospe Trail" /><published>2018-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Rospe-Trail</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Rospe-Trail">&lt;p&gt;This post contains information about “The Rospe Trail” named after my friend Rospe. It mostly uses pre existing trails in Burke Mountain, and can  be used to get to Munro and Dennett lakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to hike this trail you can park at the top of harper road. There is room for about 20-30 cars, and any time I have gone it has never been full. If it is, you could probably try parking at the gun range, but I’ve never tried that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/rospe_trail_0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rospe Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some random trail markings in different spots along this trail which can be a bit confusing, I would just ignore them completely and follow the map. If you are in doubt, head up. &lt;a href=&quot;https://caltopo.com/m/6R6C&quot;&gt;Here is a link to the map we used&lt;/a&gt;. On the way up we followed a mountain biking trail north of the marked trail because it was a lot less steep. I’d recommend it on the way up or down if you prefer not seeing the same stuff twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/rospe_trail_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rospe Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lakes are surprisingly big, and Munro lake has an awesome camping spot (not that I’m endorsing that). The site has a nice area to setup tents, and enough trees around that you could probably cowboy camp comfortably in nice weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We saw some black bears with cubs right at the trail head, but nothing much when we started to gain elevation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/rospe_trail_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rospe Trail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This post contains information about “The Rospe Trail” named after my friend Rospe. It mostly uses pre existing trails in Burke Mountain, and can be used to get to Munro and Dennett lakes. If you want to hike this trail you can park at the top of harper road. There is room for about 20-30 cars, and any time I have gone it has never been full. If it is, you could probably try parking at the gun range, but I’ve never tried that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Burke Mountain Trails</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Burke-Mountain" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burke Mountain Trails" /><published>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Burke-Mountain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2018-08/Burke-Mountain">&lt;p&gt;I am putting this post up to force myself to update it as I explore Burke Mountain. I hope to fill this post with all of the information that I can on long routes in Burke Mountain, cool places to get to, and good camp spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will do my best to upload images, and of course will include maps of all of my routes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2018-11/Dennett-Lake&quot;&gt;Dennett Lake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/posts/2018-08/Rospe-Trail&quot;&gt;Rospe Trail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am putting this post up to force myself to update it as I explore Burke Mountain. I hope to fill this post with all of the information that I can on long routes in Burke Mountain, cool places to get to, and good camp spots. I will do my best to upload images, and of course will include maps of all of my routes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ICO Concerns</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-06/ico-concerns" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ICO Concerns" /><published>2017-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-06/ico-concerns</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-06/ico-concerns">&lt;p&gt;With the recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bancor.network/&quot;&gt;Bancor&lt;/a&gt; Initial Coin Offering (ICO) raking in over 150 million USD in ETH, it is undeniable that ICO’s are huge. They are hyped throughout the community, and they often sell out within hours, minutes, or even blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2016/06/50-million-hack-just-showed-dao-human/&quot;&gt;The DAO&lt;/a&gt;” incident still fresh in the memories of many, ICO’s can be a little worrying. This post will include the common concerns relating to the rapid ICO growth, and my opinion on their validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;speed-of-sale&quot;&gt;Speed of sale&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICO’s that are extremely popular can and have sold out in only a handful of blocks. Some see this as a problem because many smaller players have trouble buying only a few tokens without spending a ridiculous amount of gas to get their transaction verified before the token is sold out. Purchasers will likely have to use a program like Parity and take advantage of its automatic sending feature to attempt to send their transaction at the exact block number that the ICO begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see this as one of the weakest arguments against the current ICO model. ICO’s are held to collect funds, and are not intended to allow everyone to have a piece of the pie. While it would be nice to allow those who only wish to purchase a small number of tokens without expending a large sum of gas, this is a problem with the platform itself, and not the ICO model. If a whale wishes to buy up 30% of the tokens in one transaction, I do not see why he/she should be limited from doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;legitimacy-and-success-rate&quot;&gt;Legitimacy and success rate&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you tell if an ICO is going to succeed? There is no foolproof method. Many like to analyze the project’s team and their past projects or contributions to the cryptography and programming world (for example, Brave).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is horrifyingly easy to make some fancy mockups and a technical whitepaper to generate interest in your project, and this is something that worries me. It would not be hard to generate interest in a facade of a technology and make away with the funds, especially with the current buzz around promising ICO’s. Auditing of project code is helpful, but not every project supplies code to be audited before a crowd sale, or the project may have no publically written code at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;dumb-money&quot;&gt;Dumb money&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another common argument about the danger of ICO’s is often called “dumb money”. When people talk about “dumb money” in the Ethereum space they are talking about people who do not have a full understanding of the technology, and rather see it as a means to get rich quick. These people could be looking for Bitcoin 2.0, or want a share in the price growths of ETH. The argument is usually based around the fact that “dumb money” generates hype around ICO’s or even ETH itself without actually understanding the technology itself, hiking the price up to an unhealthy point. They likely do not plan to use the tokens for their intended use in the ecosystem, but rather list them on exchanges as soon as they are accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;widespread-effects-of-a-failure&quot;&gt;Widespread effects of a failure&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the scariest thing about ICO’s is what happens if one fails. The effects of an ICO failure would surely have community wide ramifications, but what exactly is an ICO failure? An ICO failure could come in many different forms. Funds could be mishandled, smart contracts on the network could be exploited in a way that causes funds to be lost or stolen, a project could not make any progress with the collected funds, or many other things. A failure of a large ICO could have an effect on the price of ETH if holders sell in fear of a collapse, or leave a bad taste in the mouths of potential buyers. The network may not be ready for ICO’s, but that isn’t stopping them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens in a failure? It’s hard to say, but I am sure we will find out soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">With the recent Bancor Initial Coin Offering (ICO) raking in over 150 million USD in ETH, it is undeniable that ICO’s are huge. They are hyped throughout the community, and they often sell out within hours, minutes, or even blocks. With “The DAO” incident still fresh in the memories of many, ICO’s can be a little worrying. This post will include the common concerns relating to the rapid ICO growth, and my opinion on their validity.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">TF2 Stadium Tech Stack</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/tf2-stadium-tech-stack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TF2 Stadium Tech Stack" /><published>2017-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/tf2-stadium-tech-stack</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/tf2-stadium-tech-stack">&lt;p&gt;I originally wrote this post for an open source project I worked on called &lt;strong&gt;TF2 Stadium&lt;/strong&gt;. The post was originally available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tf2stadium.com&quot;&gt;http://blog.tf2stadium.com&lt;/a&gt;. I am re posting it now since the blog has been shut down. It is mostly semi technical information that was released as teaser/promotional content in the early stages of development. TF2Stadium is a Team Fortress 2 &lt;em&gt;lobby&lt;/em&gt; website where competitive players are matched with other players for practice matches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original post date: 03 SEP 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello, and welcome to the first actual entry of the TF2Stadium developer blog. In this entry, we will summarize some of the technology that our site uses, as well as some of our design goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The programming of TF2Stadium–as well as most other sites–is split into two major groups: “frontend” and “backend”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-frontend&quot;&gt;The Frontend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Frontend is everything from the way the page looks to the experience of using the site. The frontend is made up of HTML, CSS, and Javascript, which together form the page that a user sees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TF2Stadium is a Single Page Application, which means the entire site and most of its assets are loaded during the initial load of the page. After that, navigation does not require page loads, which in turn make the site much more responsive. This isn’t free of downsides however, such as a longer initial loading time and the necessity of using Javascript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are using AngularJS as a web framework. Web frameworks are used to remove or lessen the need for small and repetitive operations when writing code. It is a Javascript framework developed in-house by Google to produce dynamic web applications. Using AngularJS will result in cleaner and easier to maintain code. This is so we can focus on programming what we want our site to be without needing to create a coding structure first. AngularJS gives us that engine we can write on top of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided before development began to follow the principles set out by Material Design. In short, Material Design is a “Visual Language” which takes advantage of a bold and clean feel, while not sacrificing usability. The Material design spec was also developed by Google and can be seen in a lot of their products. The Angular-Material library allows our developers to create Material interfaces using the aforementioned AngularJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For styling, we use an extension called “Sass” for CSS3 (also known as SCSS). Sass is the clear choice for the project due to its relatively simple nature, and its superb maintainability. It also removes the need to repeat CSS statements throughout the stylesheets, which eliminates needless code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backend of TF2Stadium refers to everything that goes on server-side. The backend is written in the Go Programming Language. Go is developed and maintained by Google and the open source community. Recently it has seen increased adoption in the cloud with companies like Facebook, Dropbox, and Google using it in a variety of in-house projects. Go implements powerful facilities and an extensive standard library which provides a wide range of functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;for-anyone-interested-our-go-stack-uses&quot;&gt;For anyone interested, our Go stack uses:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gorilla Web Toolkit - URL routing and session cookies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ORM interface to PostgreSQL - database related operations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;go-socket.io - communication with the frontend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SimpleJSON - Go library to interact with arbitrary JSON&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;op-logging - logging framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;james4k’s rcon Go library - sending and receiving messages over the RCON protocol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;testify - testing suite (including assertions) for unit tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our interactions with TF2 are managed by two programs written by our backend team: Pauling and Helen. Helen is responsible for maintaining the database and keeping track of active lobbies and stats. It is also responsible for communicating with the frontend. Pauling handles everything related to the game servers. It connects to the game servers via RCON, then exposes an API to Helen. The API is then used to allow Helen to make Pauling send RCON commands for configuring servers, verifying connections to check if the server is still up, and executing a league config and whitelist for each server. It also listens to the server logs and notifies Helen about events like the match ending, and players connecting and disconnecting from the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also written two Go libraries: PlayerStatsScraper and TF2RconWrapper. Pauling uses TF2RconWrapper, a library written by one of our team members which wraps around james4k’s rcon for TF2-specific operations and commands. Player stats (hours played, name, and country) are retrieved using PlayerStatsScraper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-link&quot;&gt;The Link&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both parts communicate with each other through a protocol called WebSocket. This allows for a two-way conversation between the Frontend and the Backend, meaning both of them can send requests to each other which are rapidly processed without the need of a refresh in the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, Helen can tell the Frontend that a new lobby was created only once, and the latter doesn’t have to periodically ask “which lobbies are open”. It just has to react to the messages it has received. Likewise, the Frontend can notify Helen who will send a message to every user online saying “There’s a new message. Here it is.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more specific information, see &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TF2Stadium/Specifications/blob/master/Communication.md&quot;&gt;https://github.com/TF2Stadium/Specifications/blob/master/Communication.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More detailed information about the site and its features will come in our later blog entries. Until then, stay tuned on Twitter and the Steam group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want us to write a blog post about a specific topic? Tweet us, or send us suggestions on Steam or TFTV. We want to write about what the community is interested in! d in!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I originally wrote this post for an open source project I worked on called TF2 Stadium. The post was originally available at http://blog.tf2stadium.com. I am re posting it now since the blog has been shut down. It is mostly semi technical information that was released as teaser/promotional content in the early stages of development. TF2Stadium is a Team Fortress 2 lobby website where competitive players are matched with other players for practice matches. Original post date: 03 SEP 2015 Hello, and welcome to the first actual entry of the TF2Stadium developer blog. In this entry, we will summarize some of the technology that our site uses, as well as some of our design goals. The programming of TF2Stadium–as well as most other sites–is split into two major groups: “frontend” and “backend”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/hello-world" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2017-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://maccraig.net/posts/2017-02/hello-world">&lt;p&gt;First ever post on my new website. Let’s see how this goes!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">First ever post on my new website. Let’s see how this goes!</summary></entry></feed>